Guide to the Records of the California Association for Health, Physical Education, Recreation and Dance (CAHPERD), 1957-2011 M2043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 5: Title IX materials, ca. 1970-2006
  - Implementing Title IX in Physical Education and Athletics, September 1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by Barb Landers of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare.
  - Implementing Title IX and Attaining Sex Equity, September 1978 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    The materials consist of a book entitled "Implementing Title IX and Attaining Sex Equity: A Workshop Package for Elementary-Secondary Educators" written by Barb Landers and co-authored by Shirley McCune and Martha Matthews.
  - Title IX articles, 1975-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    The materials consist of a collection of newsletters & articles regarding the implementation of Title IX at national and state levels. Pat Harvey, pioneer in implementation of Title IX in LAUSD had to rely on resources from all over the country in order to influence implementation of the law.
  - Resources, 1975-1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    The materials consist of selected resources used by Specialist for Girls Athletics in Division of Intercollegiate Athletics, LAUSD.
  - Athletics Study Committee (Folder 1 of 2), 1980 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    The materials consist of agendas and minutes from the Athletic Study Committee of the California Department of Education.
  - Athletics Study Committee (Folder 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Enforcing Title IX, October 1980 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    The materials consist of a report of the US Commission on Civil Rights.
  - Title IX: The Half Full, Half Empty Glass, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by National Advisory Council on Women’s Educational Programs.
  - Title IX: A Practical Guide to Achieving Sex Equity in Education, November 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by National Coalition for Women and Girls in Education.
  - Letter to CAHPERD, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    The materials consist of a letter to P. Blatz, ED-CAHPERD, from Beverly Stunden, CAHPERD Advocacy Chair recommending changes in Title V (CA Educ. Code) regarding the implementation of Title IX.
  - Call to Action from CAHPERD’s ED, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    The materials consist of notices that were distributed periodically to enlist action by members to advocate for issues before CDE and other bodies.
  - Coverage of Women’s Sports in Four Daily Newspapers, January 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    The materials consist of a booklet from the Amateur Athletic Foundation of Los Angeles.
  - Title IX at Twenty, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    The materials consist of a reprint of a feature in Journal of Physical Education, Recreation & Dance (JOPERD).
  - The AAUW Report: How Schools Shortchange Girls, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    The materials consist of a booklet AAUW.
  - NAGWS Title IX Toolbox, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by the NAGWS.
  - GWS Title IX Toolbox Volume I and II, 1992 and 1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    The materials consist of a book produced by the GWS.
  - GWS Title IX Toolbox Volume II, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by GWS.
  - Perspectives: Journal of the Western Society for Physical Education of College Women, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by the Western Society for Physical Education of College Women.
  - Required reporting by CIF, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    The materials consist of a report on the California Interscholastic Federation.
  - Title IX at 25, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    The materials consist of a report card on gender equity.
  - The Women Sports Foundation Gender Equity Report Card, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    The materials consist of a survey of athletic opportunity in American Higher Education.
  - Title IX Reports, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Title IX at 30, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    The materials consist of a booklet produced by the National Coalition for Women and Girls in Education.
  - Letter to Congress, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    The materials consist of the CA GW's mail campaign regarding proposed changes in Title IX.
  - Final recommendations, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    The materials consist of recommendations from the Secretary of Education’s Commission on Opportunities in Athletics.
  - Women in Intercollegiate Sport study, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    The materials consist of Women in Intercollegiate Sport, A Longitudinal, National Study Twenty Nine Year Update 1977-2006 written by Vivian Acosta, PH.D. and Linda Carpenter, Ph.D.
  - Press conference, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    The materials consist of a press conference for 34th anniversary of Title IX and 20th anniversary of National Girls and Women in Sport Day.
- Series 6: CWCA complaint/lawsuit vs. CIF, 1977-1981
  Notes, legal proceedings documents, and other materials related to the lawsuit filed by the California Women's Coaches Academy against the California Interscholastic Federation. In 1978 the CWCA sued the CIF for bias against women in sports, claiming women's game officials were being paid less than the men's, women were refused jobs on the CIF governing board, and fewer girls sports programs were offered than boys sports programs. The suit was settled out of court.
  - Legal proceedings (Folder 1 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    The materials consist of legal proceedings provided by Ruth Halsey and other CWCA officers.
  - Legal proceedings (Folder 2 of 2), 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - CWCA President's notebook (Folder 1 of 3), 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - CWCA President's notebook (Folder 2 of 3), 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - CWCA President's notebook (Folder 3 of 3), 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    The materials consist of complaint notes, minutes, letters and agendas.
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 2 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 1 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 2 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 3 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - CWCA miscellaneous (Folder 4 of 4), 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - CWCA Legal Book #2 (Folder 1 of 2), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    The materials consist of CWCA complaint notes, minutes, letters and agendas.
  - CWCA Legal Book #2 (Folder 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)